Tyson "Slava" Trotz

Nashville, USA

571.732.5631 slavatrotz@gmail.com

GitHub: @Widewander LinkedIn: LinkedIn Portfolio: Widewander

Junior developer blending a background in language education with a passion for coding and technology. Earned a certificate in Full-Stack Web Development from Vanderbilt University bootcamp and supplementing IT education through online platforms including CodeAcademy and Brilliant. Diligent with consistent progress towards self-motivated learning as well as experienced in forming creative solutions to problems, in particular with the goal of improving user experience.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, GitHub, React, SQL, NoSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Node, Query, Bootstrap

LANGUAGES

English- Native, Russian- C1, Japanese - A1, Spanish- A1

PROJECTS

Profile Website

Github: https://github.com/Widewanderer/Portfolio 2.0 I

Site: https://neon-selkie-1f0b7f.netlify.app/

- · Summary: Profile website made to show personal works
- · Role: Sole author
- Tools: JavaScript, React, React Bootstrap, Node, Vite, EmailJs

Would You Rather

Github: https://github.com/Widewanderer/Would-You-Rather-Quizes I

Site: https://wyr-3b5b304bab70.herokuapp.com/

- Summary: Survey quiz website which allows users to make a profile, create and edit quizzes, and see results of other users in real time.
- Role: Front End: Created display cards and routes needed to populate their information. Added JWT capability.
- · Tools: MERN stack, React, JavaScript, Vite, Eslint, GraphQl, Apollo Client, Node.js, MongoDB

Cultured Cuisine

Github: https://github.com/Widewanderer/CulturedCuisine I

Site: https://culturedcuisine-59da43e6096e.herokuapp.com/

- Summary: Culinary website which gives users a 'cultural experience'. Recipes are classified based on culture and accompanied by cultural information.
- Role: Created general idea and layout of project. Primary technical work was in creation of "cards" to display cuisines and dishes as well as creating dynamically generating pages which display them.
- Tools: Handlebars, Node, Sequelize, MySql2, Dotenv, Bootstrap Crypt,

EXPERIENCE

Aid Trip for Ukrainian Refugees

May 2022

Raised money, organized, and lead a small group of Russian translators on an 11 day trip to Przemysl, Poland to help Ukrainian refugees.

University of the South, Sewanee

August 2021-May 2022

Russian-Eastern European Cultural Program and House Director

Provided Russian tutoring and private lessons, organized and ran Russian Cultural programs within the school, managed the Russian House, provided Russian language atmosphere for students, did administrative work of University's Russian Department

Campus 54, St. Petersburg, Russia

Fall 2018- Spring 2019

English Teacher

Taught English as a foreign language for adults focusing primarily on advanced levels.

The Serendipity American Home, Vladimir, Russia

Fall 2015 - Summer 2018

English Teacher

Taught both children and adults at varying levels from beginner to advanced both in classroom and private settings.

EDUCATION

Vanderbilt Fullstack Web-development Program

June 2023 - Dec 2023

Webdesign, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, GitHub, etc..

University of Helsinki, Helsinki, Finland

Fall 2022-2023

Master's Russian-Eurasian Studies program

The Southern Federal University, Rostov Na Don

Fall 2021- Jan 2022

Master's Degree Program in Russian Cultural Studies

Sewanee: The University of the South, Sewanee, TN

2010-2014

Bachelor's Degree in History, Bachelor's Degree in Russian

Study Abroad: Smolny Institute, St. Petersburg, Russia

Summer 2011

Semester-long comprehensive study of Russian culture, language and history through locational immersion, classroom, and host family experiences.

I-to-I TEFL Summer 2015

120 hour TEFL/ TESOL online course

Serendipity American Home: Training

August 2015, 2016,2017

Month long TEFL training session and orientation